Guide to the H. Roy Kelley papers, 1913-1965
Kelley, H. Roy papers, 1913-1965
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
H. Roy Kelley papers, 1913-1965.
3864
H. Roy (Harold Roy) Kelley, b. 1892.
14 v.
Scrapbooks and drawings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Thirteen scrapbooks of designs, articles, and photographs of residences designed by Kelley. Also, postcard-size architectural drawings done as a student at Cornell under Professor Phelps.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
H. Roy Kelley, an architect, attended Cornell University 1913-1915.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Thirteen scrapbooks of designs, articles, and photographs of residences designed by Kelley. Also, postcard-size architectural drawings done as a student at Cornell under Professor Phelps.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kelley, H. Roy (Harold Roy), b. 1892.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. College of Architecture.
Subjects:
Architecture.; Architecture--Study and teaching.; Architects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings (visual works).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Related Collection: H.R. Kelley Architectural Drawings, University of California, Santa Barbara.
CONTAINER LIST
- Scrapbook - section one, 1913-1930 (Volume 1)
- Design studies and drawings: N.Y.; Indianapolis; L.A., 1915-1917, 1920-1923 (Volume 2)
- Miscellaneous preliminary sketches and completed structures (not in chronological order), 1925-1955
  Photographs, copies of photographs, and photocopies of awards for buildings
  - William Simpson Construction Corp., no location (Volume 3)
  - Zeiler, Hammack and Maner Laboratories, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Dr. W.C.S. Koebig, designed by H.R. Kelley and Gordon B. Kaufmann, no location (Volume 3)
  - Magyar Athletic Club, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Twenty-Fifth Church of Christ Scientist, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Building for Rand Corporation, no location [Los Angeles, n.d.] (Volume 3)
  - General perspective for new Westchester School, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Proposed group of shops for Embassy Realty Associates, no location (Volume 3)
  - Preliminary scheme of new building for John Tracy Clinic (Volume 3)
  - Proposed facility for Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Proposed scheme for Ticket Office, Western Air Lines, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Perspective of front of Blums, Pasadena (Volume 3)
  - Manufacturing plant for Independent Paper Box Co., no location (Volume 3)
  - First Church of Christ Scientist, Fillmore, California (Volume 3)
  - Office and Fabricating Plant, Hickman and Ritter, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Sketch for Arthur R. Maas Laboratories, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Cyril Chappellet, Los Angeles (Bel Air) (Volume 3)
  - Residence of James Irvine, Pasadena/Altadina (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Gail and Marie Houston, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Frederic Beck, Los Angeles (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Edwin Heizmar, Palos Verdes Estates (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Robert J. Pringle, no location (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Wallace Moir, Beverly Hills (Volume 3)
  - Residence at 1135 San Marino Avenue, San Marino (Volume 3)
  - Residence of 940 Chester Avenue, San Marino (Volume 3)
  - Residence of 217 S. San Rafael Avenue, Pasadena (Pulliam) (R.W. Phillips?) (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Major Harry Lloyd Toplett, Brentwood Highlands (Volume 3)
  - F.W. Phillips, Westwood (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Dr. G.B. Baird, San Marino (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Chester C. Lincoln, San Marino (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Dr. and Mrs. Alva C. Surber, Rancho Santa Anita (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. Ralph W. Trueblood, Brentwood Park (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. A.C. Bushnell, Hollywood (Volume 3)
  - Residence of S.C. Guyer (Volume 3)
  - Residence of Mr. and Mrs. George B. Moffat (Volume 3)
- H. Roy Kelley, F.A.I.A., 1926-1931 (Volume 4)
- H. Roy Kelley, architect, Los Angeles, 1930 (Volume 5)
- Scrapbook - section two, 1930-1965 (Volume 6)
- Women's World, Apr. 1930 (Volume 7)
- H. Roy Kelley, architect, Los Angeles, 1931 (Volume 8)
- The Architect and Engineer, Sept. 1931 (Volume 9)
- H. Roy Kelley, F.A.I.A., 1931-1939 (Volume 10)
- H. Roy Kelley, architect, Los Angeles (Volume 11)
- H. Roy Kelley, architect, Los Angeles (Volume 12)
- Mr. and Mrs. J.D. Alschuler, home (Volume 13)
- H. Roy Kelley's student sketches done under Prof. Phelps (Volume 14)